Guide to the Harry H. Weintraub Collection of Gay-Related Photography and Historical Documentation, 1850s-2010.
Weintraub, Harry H. Collection of Gay-Related Photography and Historical Documentation
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harry H. Weintraub Collection of Gay-Related Photography and Historical Documentation, 1850s-2010.
7771
Harry Weintraub
89.6 cubic feet
Photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Photographs ranging from formal 19th-century portraits to candid 20th-century snapshots and Hollywood stars' studio portraits that provide a wide view of men's bodies and gay men's lives, styles, and activities from the 1850s to 2010, plus associated scrapbooks, greeting cards, programs from events, sound recordings, magazines, comic books, calendars, and ephemera. Exceeding 10,000 items in total, the collection richly documents gay male culture from many angles, featuring 1950s physique and nude photography by important studios and artists, images of drag queens, sexual activity, men together, men in the military, in athletics, and in dance, opera, and theater. Included are significant photographs of men of color and about 100 images of U.S. and European lesbians and women in drag.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Photographs ranging from formal 19th-century portraits to candid 20th-century snapshots, Hollywood stars' studio portraits, and other genres that provide a wide view of men's bodies and gay men's lives, styles, and activities from the 1850s to 2010, plus associated scrapbooks, greeting cards, programs from events, sound recordings, magazines, comic books, calendars, and ephemera. In combing flea markets and other venues for these items, which exceed 10,000 in total, the collector looked for a wide range of images reflecting gay culture and paid particular attention to acquiring photographs of men of color. In the process, he also collected about 100 images of U.S. and European lesbians and women in drag.
Prominent in the collection are physique and nude photography by Bruce of L.A., George Platt Lynes, Luis Cuento (known as Karoll of Havana), Douglas of Detroit, Dave Martin, Athletic Model Guild (Bob Mizer), Al Urban, Sierra Domino (Black men), Ralph Kelly, Lon of N.Y., Russ Warner, David Alexander Studio (Black men), Third World Studio, Champion, Colt, Target, Ritter Brothers, and others. Other strengths include photographs of drag queens, of sexual activity and S&M (sadomasochism), and of men in the military, in athletics, and in ballet, opera, and theater; the topic of crime; and portraits of men together. The collection includes unique items such as the 3 volume hand-made “Buddy's Bedside Book” created by Robert Chapman "for Robert X. McCarthy, in partial repayment for the many pleasures I owe him, on December twenty-fifth, 1957" and hand-made gay Christmas cards. Many photographs are deeply personal, and there are even a few Cornell-specific items, including a photo of a man posed in the arms of the A.D. White statue on the Arts Quad.
Periodicals include mainly physique magazines and gay erotica. Also included are calendars, sound recordings, and gay-themed comic books.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Weintraub, Harry,; Bruce of Los Angeles
Subjects:
Photography of men--United States.; Photography of the nude--United States.; Gay erotica.; Gay men; Gay men--United States; Bodybuilding
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Comic books.; Calendars.; Sound recordings.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Books cataloged individually.
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Photographs
  - The first photograph Harry Weintraub purchased, which led to the creation of this collection. Plus, other select images. (Box 1)
  - Actors
    - Small format, 420 photographs (Box A6)
  - Ads: Modern
    - Small format, 456 photographs (Box A29)
    - Small format, 25 photographs (Box A30)
  - Ads: Vintage
    - Small format, 21 photographs (Box A51)
  - Affectionate Men
    - Small format, Photographs (Box A1)
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A2)
    - Small format, 260 photographs (Box A35)
    - Small format, 19 photographs (Box A66)
      Includes cased images
    - Small format, 3 photographs (Box A97)
    - Medium format, 29 photographs (Box B1)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B168)
  - Affectionate Men/Athletes/Crime/Drag/Gay Life/Posing
    - Oversize format, Photographs (Box D2)
  - Affectionate Men/Gay Life
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C10)
  - Altman, B. Scrapbook
    - Oversize format, Items (Box D3)
      Photos removed for preservation
  - Alton Sketchbook/Kevin's Scrapbook
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B166)
  - AMG/Bob Mizer (L.A.) (Physique)
    - Small format, 480 photographs (Box A38)
    - Small format, 800 photographs (Box A57)
      Includes brochures/contact sheets
    - Small format, 400 photographs (Box A67)
    - Small format, 800 photographs (Box A77)
    - Small format, 810 photographs (Box A81)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B38)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B135)
  - Anti-gay/Crime/Violence/Guns/Runaways/Medical/Disabled/Toreadors/Artist and Model
    - Small format, 350 photographs (Box A47)
  - Art Work/Prints/Drawings/Paintings/Posing (Russ Warner)/Posters
    - Oversize format, Items (Box D5)
  - Athletes/Teams
    - Small format, 290 photographs (Box A8)
      Includes baseball, basketball, cheerleading, diving, football, golf, lifeguards, swimming, tennis, track and field, water skiing
    - Small format, 80 photographs (Box A69)
      Includes acrobats, balancing acts, trapeze
    - Small format, 384 photographs (Box A92)
      Includes body builders, weight lifters
    - Medium format, 60 photographs (Box B6)
      Includes baseball, basketball, cheerleading, diving, football, golf, gymnastics, lifeguards, swimming, tennis, track and field
    - Medium format, 81 photographs (Box B40)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B49)
      Includes body builders, boxers, weight lifters, wrestlers
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B77)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B78)
    - Medium format, 72 photographs (Box B79)
      Includes crew, rowing
    - Medium format, 20 photographs (Box B99)
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C15)
      Includes body builders
  - Avelenda, Joe (NYC): Correspondence
    - Medium format, 61 items (Box B66)
  - Bagnato, Gene (NYC)
    - Small format, 278 photographs (Box A5)
  - Bentz, Sean (L.A.)
    - Medium format, 29 photographs (Box B137)
  - Bernardo, John and Friends (Coney Island, NY)
    - Small format, 134 photographs (Box A91)
  - Blade
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B112)
  - Bodybuilding Literature/Charles Atlas Course/Earle Leiderman
    - Medium format, Items (Box B126)
      Pamphlets on weight lifting and body health, barbell brochures, Earle E. Leiderman items.
  - Body parts / portraits
    - Medium format, Photographs, 1 framed portrait (Box B174)
  - Braun, Stephen F. (Shield #11523) Collection/ Womanless Wedding Scrapbook
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B167)
  - Brian, J.
    - Medium format, 2 photographs (Box B18)
  - Brian, J. and Champion/Walter Kundzicz (NYC)
    - Small format, 228 photographs (Box A72)
  - Bruce of L.A./Bruce Bellas (Physique)
    Bruce Bellas (1909 – 1974) began photographing bodybuilders in Los Angeles, California in 1947. He became known as Bruce of L.A., launched his own magazine, Male Figure, in 1956, and is remembered as an influential photographer of the male figure.
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A12)
      Includes 5x7 photographs
    - Small format, 350 photographs (Box A14)
    - Small format, 353 photographs (Box A18)
      Includes 4x5 photographs
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A25)
    - Small format, Photographs (Box A31)
    - Small format, 400 photographs (Box A32)
    - Small format, 63 photographs (Box A86)
    - Medium format, 130 photographs (Box B10)
    - Medium format, 52 photographs (Box B16)
    - Medium format, 5 photographs (Box B22)
    - Medium format, 104 photographs (Box B25)
    - Medium format, 338 photographs (Box B48)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B50)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B63)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B134)
  - Bruce of L.A./Bruce Bellas/Kensington Road (KR)
    Included here are photographs distributed during Bruce of L.A.'s lifetime, and also by a mail order distributor Kensington Road after his death. Once postal laws against sending male frontal nudity through the U.S. postal service were lifted, Kensington Road was able to share with mass markets Bruce's more explicit images.
    - Small format, 290 photographs (Box A23)
    - Small format, 88 photographs (Box A52)
  - Buddy's Bedside Book: Volumes I, II, & III
    - Medium format, Items (Box B144)
      "For Robert X. McCarthy, in partial repayment for the many pleasures I owe him, on December twenty-fifth, 1957" (chap books created by Robert Chapman, director of Loeb Theater at Harvard)
  - Cabinet Cards and other images of Handsome Men
    - Small format, 200 photographs (Box A61)
    - Small format, 15 photographs (Box A89)
  - Clergy/Altar Boys/Church-related/Jesus/Saints
    - Medium format, 65 photographs (Box B45)
  - Clothing/Leather/Toys/Hotels/Resorts/Travel/Books/Brochures/Catalogues
    - Medium format, Includes items by: Accu-Jac [T], Ah Men (West Hollywood), Apres Noir (Santa Rosa, CA)[C/F], Blueboy (Miami)[B], Blueboy Library (Santee, CA)[B], Blueboy Lifestyle Travel Division (Miami) [T], The Cloak & Dagger (SF)[L], Donhar Printing & Publishing Co. (Hollywood)[GC], Editions Aubrey Walter (London)[B], T.J. Ferrick Co. (Newburyport, MA)[R], Conrad Germain [C], Guild Book Service (WDC/Norfolk)[B], Hobbies of Houston [C], International Male (L.A.), Kris Studio (Chicago)[C/L], Lambda International Association, Ltd.(WDC)[T], The Lauderdale Beach Hotel [H], The Living End Catalogue (NYC) [T], Tony Llad (Chicago)[L], MMB (Santee, CA), P.C. Leathers Ltd. (NYC) [T], Parr of Arizona (Phoenix)[C], Philmar (Hollywood)[C], R.F.M. (Canandaigua, NY) [L/R/T], Regency Square (Hollywood) [C], Patterson Smith (East Orange, NJ)[R], Spartan House [B], E.A. Stanley Ltd. (London)[C], Studstore/Mr. S Products (SF)[C/L/T], Tag (Hollywood)[GC], That Look (L.A.)[B], Vagabond Sales (Minneapolis)[GC], Village Books & Press [B] (Box B119)
  - Colorized Xeroxes of Celebrities/Celebrity Sexcapades
    - Medium format, 15 items (Box B17)
  - Colt/Jim French (NYC)
    - Small format, 350 photographs (Box A55)
  - Comic/Bizarre/Tinted
    - Small format, 336 photographs (Box A48)
  - Comic/Bizarre/Medical/Tinted/Anti-gay/Political/Gay History/Violence/Guns/Disabled/Artist and Models/Christmas
    - Medium format, 114 items (Box B5)
      Includes Cock Robin, calendars, 45rpms
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B156)
  - Crime/Runaways/Prison
    - Medium format, 35 photographs (Box B162)
  - Cuban/Karoll
    - Medium format, 95 photographs (Box B82)
  - Dance/Theatre/Opera/Concert Programs
    - Large format, Items (Box C11)
  - Dancers/Choreographers
    - Medium format, 120 photographs (Box B14)
  - Dancers/Musicians/Visual Artists/Writers
    - Small format, 93 photographs (Box A17)
  - Drag
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C16)
  - Drag: Male and Female/Drag Bars and Clubs
    - Small format, 309 photographs (Box A15)
    - Medium format, 147 photographs (Box B2)
    - Medium format, 97 photographs (Box B80)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B169)
      Includes image of Four Black drag queens ca. 1940s, digital file HWX_0052, used in Speaking of Sex exhibition.
  - Drawings/Prints/Book Plates/Non-photo Publications/Anatomical (Non-porn)
    - Medium format, Items (Box B34)
  - DuPuis, John Paul Scrapbook/Joseph D'Eredita ("Artist's Model")
    - Large format, Items (Box C23)
  - E.M.A. Studio/Ed McAndrews (L.A.)
    - Small format, 480 photographs (Box A79)
    - Small format, 200 photographs (Box A84)
      Includes 5x7 photographs and scrapbook
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B111)
      Includes 8x10 photographs
  - Ethnic/Statuary/Fine Art/Naturist/Artist and Model/Gay Collecting: Vintage
    - Small format, 350 items (Box A37)
      Includes Art Catalogues and Pierrot
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B36)
  - Film Portraits/Stills
    - Medium format, 127 photographs (Box B4)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B51)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B55)
    - Medium format, 86 photographs (Box B67)
    - Medium format, 121 photographs (Box B71)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B75)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B95)
    - Medium format, 200 photographs (Box B107)
    - Medium format, 118 photographs (Box B114)
    - Medium format, 186 photographs (Box B136)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B140)
  - Film portraits/Stills/Window Cards
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C13)
  - Fire Island: 1950s and 1960s
    - Medium format, 53 photographs (Box B138)
  - Fraternities/College/Hazing/Clubs/Summer Camps
    - Small format, 91 photographs (Box A58)
    - Medium format, 107 photographs (Box B61)
      See Scrapbooks
  - Gay Art: Brochures
    - Medium format, Items (Box B132)
      Includes brochures by: Art-Bob (L.A.), Colt Studio/Adam/Rip Colt (NYC), Carl Corley, Etienne, Inca Industries (Hollywood), Will Lees (NYC), Luger Studios/Kurt Luger (NYC), Wm. MacLane Studios (Seattle), Quaintance, Tom Rain, Thor (Chicago), Vorton Studios (Chicago), Ken Wallace, Wessart (Portland, OR)
  - Gay Art: Non-porn
    - Small format, 98 photographs (Box A13)
  - Gay Art: Porn
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A4)
      Includes COMM, ID, 4x5, and 5x7 photographs of: Art-Bob (L.A.), Blade, Jean Boullet, Roland Caillaux, Colt, Drabskin, Etienne/Stephen, Martin (NDR), Masters/Miksche, Tom of Finland, John Palatino (NYC), Jean Vincent, Waugh (for ID)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B92)
      Includes ID photographs by: Art Bob, Blade, Jean Boullet, Rolan Caillaux, Colt, Carl Crale (sp?), Rod Crowther, Duane, Etienne/Stephen, Happy Face, Luger, W. MacLane, Ed McLeod, Peter, Quaintance, Quam, Paul Smara, The Sophisticate (Glassboro, NJ), Soungouroff, Spartacus, Thor, Jean Vincent, Waugh (for ID)
    - Medium format, 90 photographs (Box B128)
      Includes ID, UNID photographs by: Jesse Dean (NYC), Graewolf, Masters/Miksche
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B129)
      Includes ID photographs by: Etienne, Luger, Spartacus
  - Gay Art: Porn Publications
    - Medium format, Items (Box B139)
      Includes items by: A. Jay, Rex, Sean
  - Gay & Lesbian Newspapers
    - Oversize format, Items (Box D1)
    - Oversize format, Items (Box D4)
  - Gay Life: Modern
    - Small format, 211 photographs (Box A10)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B52)
  - Gay Life: Vintage
    - Small format, 336 photographs (Box A3)
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A9)
    - Small format, 323 photographs (Box A42)
    - Small format, 146 photographs (Box A59)
      Includes sets
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A76)
    - Small format, 110 photographs (Box A87)
    - Medium format, 97 photographs (Box B11)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B57)
    - Medium format, 29 photographs (Box B65)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B76)
    - Medium format, 100 photographs (Box B83)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B149)
  - Gay Life/Posing: Vintage
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B47)
  - Gay Political Cards/Notices
    - Small format, 63 items (Box A11)
      Includes postcards and printed ephemera on subjects including safe sex, HIV, gays in the military, "ca. 1998 U.S. Don't Ask Don't Tell" policy. Also 1979 Italian postcard of Valentino for publishers' event.
  - Geissenheimer, Harold Collection
    - Small format, 113 items (Box A90)
  - Grand Tour Scrapbook
    - Small format, 200 items (Box A83)
  - Greeting Cards/Postcard Reproductions: Modern
    - Small format, 232 items (Box A45)
    - Small format, 450 items (Box A64)
    - Small format, 200 items (Box A80)
    - Small format (Box A94)
    - Medium format, Items (Box B53)
  - Greeting Cards: Vintage
    - Small format, 300 items (Box A44)
  - Greyhuff Review
    - Medium format, Items (Box B69)
      Includes 1st and 3rd Editions
  - Hanson, K.
    - Medium format, 49 photographs (Box B68)
      Includes 4x5, 5x7, 8x10 photographs
  - Judaica
    - Medium format, photographs (Box B172)
      Postcards, including anti-Semitic, Jewish Welfare Board of the U.S. military, Jewish buildings and individuals, Poliacoff's Kosher restaurant, Kaplan's Hebrew National Delicatessen. A 1941 anti-Hitler New Year's card from the Hockman family. Pamphlets, 1920s-50s. Miscellaneous manuscript and print items, 1907-1949, including on crimes, on Kosher meat, on Jewish refugees in 1924. And 3 photographs of scenes from a Yiddish movie.
  - Kelly, Ralph (L.A.)
    - Small format, 230 photographs (Box A62)
  - Kris/Charles Renslow (Chicago)
    - Small format, 340 photographs (Box A46)
      Includes 4x5, 5x7 photographs
  - Lesbiana
    - Medium format, 94 photographs, 1 pamphlet, 1 album (Box B13)
      Some postcard format photos. Includes 1930-55 photos of Wellesley College's crew team showing "that crew members are every bit as cute and hfeminine as their less athletic classmates," single and group poses of females in male clothes, women together, mostly 1900-1940; one Tijuana Bible on a theme of lesbian sex, "dan Dunn;" one personal photo album.
  - Lynch, Mark (Austin, TX)
    - Small format, 300 photographs (Box A78)
    - Medium format, 132 photographs (Box B29)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B125)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B145)
      Includes Polaroid photographs with applications
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B146)
      Includes Polaroid photographs
  - George Platt Lynes, 1930-1955; Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955
    Photographs including portraits, nudes, and one still-life by photographer George Platt Lynes.
    - Male Nudes, 1941-1951; Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955; 25.4 x 20.3. cm, 17.8 x 12.7 cm; 97 photographs (Box B173)
      Contains erotic photographs of male nudes.
      Photography of men
      Photography, erotic
      Gelatin silver prints
      Chromogenic color prints
    - Jacques d'Amboise, 1935-1940; 2 photographs (Box C24, Folder 1)
      Portrait photography
      - Two nude men, 1935-1940; 25.6 x 20.4 cm (Box C24, Folder 1)
        D'Amboise, Jacques, 1934-
        Lynes, George Platt, 1907-1955
      - Jacques d'Amboise, 1935-1940; 25.6 x 20.6 cm (Box C24, Folder 1)
    - Ruth Ford, 1940-1950; 25.3 x 20.3 cm; 3 photographs (Box C24, Folder 2)
      Ford, Ruth, 1911-2009
    - John Hohnsbeen, 1940-1950; 20.5 x 25.5 cm; 3 photographs (Box C24, Folder 3)
    - Tanaquil Le Clercq, 1945-1950; 19 x 23.5 cm; 2 photographs (Box C24, Folder 4)
      Le Clercq, Tanaquil
    - Wilbur Pippin, 1940-1950; 17.8 x 11.5 cm, 23.8 x 18.5 cm, 35.5 x 28 cm; 5 photographs (Box C24, Folder 5)
      Pippin, Wilbur
    - Aldous Huxley, 1947; 33.6 x 26.7 cm; 2 photographs (Box C24, Folder 6)
      Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963
    - Alfred C. Kinsey, 1946-1950; 35.3 x 28.2 cm; 3 photographs (Box C24, Folder 7)
      Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles), 1894-1956
    - W. H. Auden, 1935-1950; 35.5 x 28.1 cm; 3 photographs (Box C24, Folder 8)
      Auden, W.H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973
    - Kay Thompson, 1948; 35.4 x 28.2 cm; 2 photographs (Box C24, Folder 9)
      Thompson, Kay, 1909-1998
    - Named portraits, 1935-1950; 12 photographs (Box C24, Folder 10)
      - Rory Calhoun, 1935-1950; 35.4 x 28.2 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Calhoun, Rory, 1922-1999
      - Marsden Hartley, 1940-1950; 33.2 x 26.7 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Hartley, Marsden, 1877-1943
      - Todd Bolender, 1945-1950; 32.6 x 27 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Bolender, Todd
      - Isabel Bolton, 1935-1950; 31 x 26.5 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Bolton, Isabel, 1883-1975
      - Margaret Hamilton, 1935-1945; 35.4 x 28.2 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Hamilton, Margaret, 1902-1985
      - Gertrude Stein, 1935-1950; 27.9 x 35.3 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946
      - Maria Tallchief, 1945-1950; 28.8 x 15.2 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Tallchief, Maria
      - Jessica Tandy, 1947; 35.5 x 28.2 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Tandy, Jessica
      - Joseph Platt, 1930-1950; 33.6 x 26.3 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
      - Thomas Mann, 1945-1950; 35.3 x 28 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955
      - Marc Chagall, 1930-1940; 33.6 x 26.7 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
        Chagall, Marc, 1887-1985
      - Fedoris Palvacinni, 1930-1950; 23.8 x 18.6 cm (Box C24, Folder 10)
    - Unnamed Portraits, 1930-1950; 19.8 x 24.5 cm, 35.5 x 28 cm; 8 photographs (Box C24, Folder 11)
    - Still Lifes, 1930-1950; 1 photograph (Box C24, Folder 12)
      Still-life photography
  - Martin, Dave (SF)
    - Medium format, 58 photographs (Box B27)
    - Medium format, 117 photographs (Box B41)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B42)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B103)
  - Melan, Lou/Louis Melancon (NYC)
    - Medium format, 350 photographs (Box B30)
  - Milie, William
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B171)
  - Military
    - Small format, Photographs (Box A49)
    - Small format, 161 photographs (Box A56)
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A63)
    - Small format, 450 photographs (Box A68)
    - Small format, 400 photographs (Box A85)
    - Medium format, 33 photographs (Box B3)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B60)
    - Medium format, 72 photographs (Box B74)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B98)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B170)
  - Milo of Los Angeles/Pat Milo (Bodybuilding)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B54)
  - Miscellaneous Images
    - Medium format, 9 photographs (Box B73)
    - Medium format, black and white, mostly studio, photographs (Box B85)
  - Miscellaneous Objects
    - Small format, 30 items (Box A7)
      Includes playing cards, "Gay bobbie pins" etc.
    - Medium format, 20 items (Box B90)
  - Negatives/Slides
    - Medium format, 36 items (Box B15)
  - Ness, Neil R. Collection/Studio 54
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C21)
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C22)
  - Non-photo Publications
    - Medium format, 180 items (Box B12)
      Includes "Broadway Brevities", Mattachine Society, letters, public health & hygiene, military
  - Old Reliable
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B123)
  - Other, Non-Gay Related
    - Small to Medium format, Celebrity Photographs, Books, Poster (Box B175)
  - Pippin, Wilbur
    - Medium format, photographs (Box B173)
    - Large format, photographs (Box C25)
  - Places: YMCAs/Gay Bars/Gay Resorts/Baths/Cruising Spots/Postcard Messages
    - Small format, 110 items (Box A22)
    - Medium format, 8 items (Box B97)
  - Porno/Physique Industry
    - Medium format, 162 photographs (Box B43)
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C12)
  - Pornography: pre-1950s
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B164)
  - Portraits: Choreographers/Dancers/Musicians/Visual Artists/Writers/Non-Artists
    - Large format, Photographs (Box C6)
  - Portraits: Non-artists
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B21)
  - Portraits: Non-film Actors/Art Dealers/Designers/Opera/Models/Musicians/Visual Artists/Writers/Burlesque
    - Medium format, 338 photographs (Box B19)
    - Medium format, Photographs (Box B142)
  - Posing
    - Small format, 376 photographs (Box A19)